

online

languages

english (proficient) mandarin

programming

Python, JavaScript, Java, Ruby, C, Perl

technical skills

HTML & CSS, LATEX, Linux System Administration ✓ DOB: 1987/12/17 <a>∅ (+1) 514 562-7375

about

I'm currently a Masters student at the University of Montreal, where I work at the Montreal Institute of Learning Algorithms (MILA). I enjoy working on machine learning projects, and keeping up with the latest in neural networks research. I maintain a blog where I write about my machine learning projects.

research interests

Semantics3

artificial intelligence, recurrent neural networks, machine learning, reinforcement learning, graphical models, natural language processing, data mining

experience

2013-2014

2010-2012

2016-present	Montreal Institute for Learning Algorithms, University of Montreal	Masters Student
	Working on deep learning research.	
2014-2016	Speech Recognition Group, National University of Singapore Working on the machine learning aspects of speech recognition usin with applications to speaker adaptation and noise robustness.	Research Assistant g neural networks,

• Classification of products into a hierarchical taxonomy using a cascading naive bayes model built using the Lucene index.

Software/Data Engineer

Undergraduate researcher

- Name equivalency model used as part of the disambiguation process to determine if two product names are referring to the same thing.
- Experimented with using conditional random fields for attribute extraction from product names.

	Did two undergraduate research projects (see next page)	
2008-2009	Singapore Armed Forces	Manpower Officer
	Administrative position managing National Servicemen	
01-06 2007	RHyMeS Center, Ngee Ann Polytechnic	Research/Teaching Assistant

Web Information Retrieval and NLP Group (WING), NUS

- Provided technical support for students working on the RHyMeS project.
- Facilitated workshops on using the RHyMeS SDK and API.
- Taught students working on their projects how to use the Java Swing UI API

education

2016-present Masters of Computer Science

University of Montreal

2009-2012 **Bachelors of Computing (BComp)** National University of Singapore

Major in Computer Science - Upper 2nd Class Honours Special Programme in Computing (Turing Programme)

Focus Area: Artificial Intelligence

CAP: 4.39 / 5

2004-2007 **Diploma in Information Technology**

Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore

Specialisation in Software Engineering - Diploma with Merit

GPA: 3.8 / 4

2003 **GCE '0' Levels**

Mayflower Secondary School, Singapore

projects

10 2014 Neural Turing Machines implementation in Theano

Implementation of system described in "Neural Turing Machines." by Alex Graves, Greg

Wayne, and Ivo Danihelka.

2012 **Predicting Web 2.0 Thread Updates**

A method to estimate arrival times of new posts to forum discussion threads and an evaluation metric for measuring the effectiveness of an incremental crawler of a site with

time-sensitive data.

04 2012 Focused Web Crawling using Markov Decision Processes

Using the least-squares policy iteration algorithm and some heuristics to perform focused

crawling. For CS4246R AI for Planning and Decision Making (Research Project)

2010 - 2011 grabsmart: A User-centric Web Information Extraction System

An integrated system that allows users to easily select portions of a page to extract, and

subsequently extracts the data in a manner that is robust to site layout changes.

04 2011 LSPI Tetris Agent

Application of the least-squares policy iteration algorithm to play Tetris as part of the CS3243 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence course. The agent can complete 100,000

lines on average, and up to a maximum of about a million lines.

organisations

2010-2012 **NUS Hackers** Coreteam Member (Member of Executive Committee)

Duties include facilitating NUS Hacker activities: Hack & Roll 2012, Friday Hacks (a weekly tech talk), and maintaining the download.nus.edu.sg mirror service.

2003-2012 **Singapore Scouts Association**

Assistant Venture Scout Leader

Attached to the Mayflower Secondary School Boy Scouts Group. Duties a include facilitating camps, weekly meetings, and mentoring both scouts and ventures.